Inventory of the James Barron Papers (1) 1776-1899
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Box 6, 1824. (Box-folder 6:1-68)
  - Letter - Della[?] Stokes, Norfolk, to Comdr. James Barron, 12 January 1823., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:1)
    Request for a loan.
  - Letter - Dr. P[hilip] Barraud to James Barron, Navy Yard, [Norfolk], 27 January 1823., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:2)
    Invitation to meet the son of John Marshall.
  - Letters - William Craig, Philadelphia, to Commodore James Barron, Norfolk, January-September 1823., 7 letters. ALsS. (Box-folder 6:3)
    Business letters; mention of a spinning machine invented by Barron.
  - Letter - Const. Freeman, Treasury Department, to Capt. James Barron, Norfolk, 8 February 1823., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:4)
    Enclosing payment for a requisition signed by the Secretary of the Navy plus his regular pay.
  - Letter - J.D. Elliott, New York, to Como. James Barron, Philadelphia, 18 February 1823., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:5)
    Barron is in Philadelphia to consult Dr. Phisicle.
  - Letter - Carter Beverly, Williamsburg, to Commodore James Barron, Norfolk, 23 February 1823., 7 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:6)
    Re: his faith in Barron and his defense of him in private conversations.
  - Letter - A. Rodney, Wilmington, Delaware, to Capt. James Barron, Norfolk, 12 April 1823., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:7)
    Re: personal affairs.
  - Letter - Comdr. Edm'd Primrose Kennedy, "Palestine," to Comdre. James Barron, Norfolk, 19 April 1823., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:8)
  - Letters - Carolina Colbiornsen, St. Croix, to Commodore Ja[me]s Barron, Norfolk, April-October 1823., 3 letters. ALsS. (Box-folder 6:9)
    Personal affairs concerned with friends in Copenhagen.
  - Letters - Ch. W. Goldsborough to Commre. James Barron, Norfolk, April-November 1823., 2 copies. PL, ES. (Box-folder 6:10)
    Announcement of the "United States Naval Chronicle" with endorsement, signed.
  - Letter - Ch. W. Goldsborough, Washington, to James Barron, Norfolk, 18 November 1823., ALS. (Box-folder 6:11)
    This letter was enclosed with the above announcement, located in Box-folder: 6:10.
  - Letter - Carter Beverly, Fredericksburg, to Commodore James Barron, Norfolk, 6 May 1823., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:12)
    "The course... of the Executive of our country against you calls loudly for... indignation."
  - Letter - James Barron, Bayside, to his daughter, Mrs. Jane A. Hope, 20 July 1823., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:13)
    Re: some great sorrow that has befallen the family.
  - Letter - F. Taylor, Old Point Comfort, to [James Barron], 20 October 1823., 1 page. ALS,E. (Box-folder 6:14)
    Introducing Dr. French; endorsement, "who married Miss Elizabeth Barron."
  - A. Fibigen, Copenhagen, to Commodore James Barron, 18 November 1823., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:15)
    Re: canvas sold in America for which he has not been paid; and sympathy for Barron and "the intrigues of your enemies."
  - James Barron, Norfolk, to Thomas Newton, 27 November 1823., 4 pages. ADrS. (Box-folder 6:16)
    Re: his "miserable situation": his constant application for some employment, his visits with [President Monroe], and the lack of any response from the Navy Department.
  - Letter - R. J. Cleveland, New York, to James Barron, U.S. Navy, Norfolk, Virginia, l December 1823., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:17)
    Reports in detail his losses in a disastrous sailing venture in the Pacific.
  - Letter - John W. Eaton, Washington, to Commodore James Barron, Norfolk, 23 December 1823., ALS. 2 pages. (Box-folder 6:18)
    Gives hope that "the next incumbent of the White House may venture to look to your claim."
  - Letter - William Craig, Philadelphia, to Commodore James Barron, Washington City, 28 December 1823., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:19)
    Re: Barron's trip to Washington to claim his rights; and possibility that General Jackson will be Pennsylvania's candidate for the Presidency.
  - Letter - G. P. French, Hampton, to Commodore James Barron, Washington, 10 January 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:20)
    He has commended Barron to Mr. Forsythe of the U.S. Congress.
  - Letter - Capt. E.P. Kennedy, U.S. Ship Harnet, to Commodore John Rogers, Pres. Navy Board, Washington, 14 January 1824., 2 pages. Cop of AL. (Box-folder 6:21)
    Re: the bellows invented by Barron for ventilating ships.
  - Letter - John S. Crawford, Gettysburg, to Captain James Barron, Washington, 19 January 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:22)
    Asks horticultural information.
  - Letters - William Craig, Philadelphia, to Commodore James Barron, Washington and Gospart, Virginia, January-April 1824., 3 letters. ALsS. (Box-folder 6:23)
    Re: the support that Gen'l Jackson has given Barron; and Jackson's candidacy for President.
  - Letters - J.D. Elliott, Norfolk, to Como. James Barron, Washington and Philadelphia, January-September 1824., 4 letters. ALsS. (Box-folder 6:24)
    Re: Barron's claims in Washington, his support by Gen'l Jackson, and his appointment as Commander to the Philadelphia Navy Yard.
  - Letter - John P. Tuttle, U.S. Ship John Adams, passing Crony Island, to [James Barron], Washington, 17 February 1824., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:25)
    Re: his wife, the former Margaretta Barron, and his family.
  - Letter - John Taliaferro, Hagley, to [?], 2 March 1824., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:26)
    He expresses his sympathy with James Barron in his persecution and states his intention of bringing the matter before the Secretary of the Navy.
  - Letters - James Barron, Norfolk, to Captain Linus Worrington, U.S. Navy, Gosport, Virginia, 25 March 1824., 1 page. ADrS. (Box-folder 6:27)
    Re: the installation of bellows [for ventilation] on the ship commanded by Capt. Kennedy.
  - Letters - J.B. Mower, Washington and New York, to James Barron, Norfolk and Philadelphia, March-August 1824., 5 letters. ALsS. (Box-folder 6:28)
    Re: the Navy Bill before Congress; the nomination of Jackson as the candidate for President of the U.S.; add Barron's appointment to the Commander of the Philadelphia Navy Yard.
  - Letter - James Barron, Norfolk, to Joseph Delaplain, Philadelphia, 7 April 1824., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:28a)
    Concerning his ancestors and his present predicament.
  - Letter - [R.K. Carl] to Comdr. James Barron, U.S. Navy, Norfolk, Virginia, 13 April 1824., 1 page. AL. (Box-folder 6:29)
    Reports, "we feel confident now we shall have the notes of Georgia."
  - Letter - Horace Binney to James Barron, 23 April 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:30)
    An invitation to dinner.
  - Letter - T. Gatewood, Norfolk, to Commodore James Barron, Philadelphia, 11 May 1824., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:31)
    Re: Naval matters.
  - Letter - J.B. Mower, Washington, to Charles G. Haines, New York, 20 May 1824., 1 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:32)
    A letter of introduction for Comm. James Barron.
  - Letter - [J.D.?] E[lliott] franked "H.L. Pinckney" to Com. [James] Barron, Commander, Navy Yard, Philadelphia, 29 June 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:33)
    Social note.
  - Letter - J.G. Collins & Son, New York, to Commodore Ja[me]s Barron, U.S. Navy, Norfolk, Virginia, v, pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:34)
    Re: the availability of corkwood for the making of bottle corks.
  - Invitation - from the City of Richmond to Commodore James Barron, Philadelphia, 22 July 1824., 1 page. PLS. (Box-folder 6:35)
    To meet General Lafayette, signed by John Adams, Mayor, and by Wm. Fitzwhylson and Tho. Brockenbrough.
  - Application - W. Taylor, Norfolk, to Captain James Barron, Philadelphia, 30 July 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:36)
    Application for the position of Secretary to Barron should he be called back into active service, which seems to be imminent.
  - Letter - Josiah Cowper, Norfolk, to Captn. James Barron, Philadelphia, 8 August 1824., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:37)
    Expresses gratification that Barron has been called into active service by the "good old President."
  - Letter - John Colt, Paterson, to Comre. Ja[me]s Barron, Philadelphia, 12 August 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:38)
    Re: twilled cotton; and congratulations "on your recent change of situation."
  - Letter - G. P. French, Hampton, to Comdre. James Barron, Philadelphia, 13 August 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:39)
    Expresses "joy at the termination of your unmerited persecution."
  - Letter - J.G. Collins & Son, New York, to Commodore James Barron, Philadelphia, 13 August 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:40)
    Re: an order for corkwood.
  - Letter - Butler Maury, Norfolk, to Commodore James Barron, U.S. Navy, Philadelphia, 15 August 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:41)
    Rejoices "that you are restored to a station in the Service to which you have been so long and so justly entitled."
  - Letter - J. Mason, Old Point Comfort, to Commodore [James] Barron, Philadelphia, 17 August 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:42)
    Appreciation for the gift of a spyglass.
  - Letter - J. Cowper, Norfolk, to Captn. James Barron, Philadelphia, 18 August 1824., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:43)
    Re: "the friendly manner the good old President received you," and "the conduct of the two scoundrels that has come out against you in Philadelphia."
  - Letter - W. Knight, Philadelphia, to Commodore James Barron, Philadelphia, 20 August 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:44)
    Complaining about too heavy duties in the Navy Yard (of which Barron is commander).
  - Letters - R. J. Cleveland, Lancaster, [Massachuetts], to James Barron, Philadelphia, August-October 1824., 3 letters. ALsS. (Box-folder 6:45)
    Re: the appointment of Barron as Commander of the Philadelphia Navy Yard and of the resentment of some persons in Philadelphia.
  - Letter - Andrew Jackson, "Hermitage," near Nashville, to Com[m]odore James Barron, of the Station and Navy Yard of Philadelphia, 14 September 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:46)
    "If my candor to Mr. Monroe had any effect in the application of the Golden Law (of justice) be assured it is a great satisfaction to me."
  - Letter - "A female, (a) friend to the Navy," Philadelphia, to Commo. James Barron, U.S. Navy, present, 20 September 1824., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:47)
    Accusation against some of the officers of the Yard.
  - Letter - Major General Cadwalader, to Commodore [James] Barron, 22 September 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:48)
    An invitation to meet General Lafayette.
  - Letter - Benj[amin] Tilghman and W[illia]m Rush to Commodore James Barron, Philadelphia, 25 September 1824., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:49)
    Gratitude from the committee appointed to receive General Lafayette, for the Naval salutes ordered by Barron.
  - Letter - B[enjamin] Tilghman, Trenton, to Commodore James Barron, Philadelphia, 26 September 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:50)
    Re: a request by General Lafayette that a visit be made to the Naval Yard. (under the Command of Barron).
  - Tickets - for Commodore [James] Barron to be admitted to the reception of Gen. Lafayette at the Hall of Independence, 28 September 1824., 2 tickets. PAM. (Box-folder 6:51)
    Signed by J.A.S. Lewis, Chairman. Enclosed envelopes in which the tickers were enclosed, endorsed. AC.
  - Letter - [?] to Commodore [James] Barron, [September 1824]., 2 pages. AD,E. (Box-folder 6:52)
    Endorsed: "List of invited guests to dine with General Lafayette."
  - Letter - Robert C. Cutler, Nelson County, Virginia, to Com. James Barron, Philadelphia, 1 October 1824., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:53)
    "Your appointment gives all the people of this county much satisfaction."
  - Letter - [?] Gatewood, Norfolk, to Como. James Barron, Philadelphia, 6 October 1824., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:54)
    Re: events around Norfolk.
  - Letter - Robert Beverly, George Town, to Commore. James Barron, Philadelphia, 8 October 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:55)
    Sympathy with Barron and daughters in their bereavement; and a notice of a runaway servant.
  - Letter - Dr. P[hilip] Barraud, Norfolk, Virginia, to Commodore [James] Barron, Navy Yard, Philadelphia, 10 October 1824., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:56)
    Sympathy in his sorrow.
  - Letter - A. McLand, Washington, D.C., to Commr. James Barron, Philadelphia, 11 October 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:57)
    Re: a planned visit to Yorktown.
  - Letter - E. R. McCall, Philadelphia, to Com. James Barron, U.S. Navy, Philadelphia, 26 October 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:58)
    Re: a leave of absence.
  - Invitation - Charles D. McIndoe, Petersburg, to Commodore[James] Barron, 29 October 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:59)
    An invitation to a ball honoring General Lafayette. Card of admission enclosed.
  - Letter - R.C. Cutler, Lovingston, Virginia, to Com. James Barron, Philadelphia, 30 October 1824., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:60)
    Re: the Yorktown celebration and social news.
  - Report - Capt. Kennedy, Havanna, to Comdre. James Barron, Philadelphia, 4 November 1824., 2 pages. Cop of AL. (Box-folder 6:61)
    A report on the ship's ventilators invented by Barron.
  - Letter - Capt. Kennedy to Comdre. J[ames] Barron, 4 November 1824., 2 pages. Cop of AL. (Box-folder 6:62)
    A covering letter for the above.
  - Letter - Clara S. Cutbush, West Point, to Capt. James Barron, Philadelphia, 4 November 1824., 2 pages. ALS,P. (Box-folder 6:63)
    Re: a book on "System of Pyrotechny" by her late husband, James Cutbush, written on fold of the printed prospectus.
  - Notice - to Commodore James Barron that he has been elected an honorary member of the New York Horticultural Society, signed by David Hosack, President, 13 November 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:64)
  - Request - John Crawford, Gettysburg, to Commodore James Barron, Philadelphia, 24 November 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:65)
    Request for recommendation for position of Sergeant at Arms of the House of Representatives.
  - Letter - G.W. Lafayette, to Commodore [James] Barron, Philadelphia, 26 November 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:66)
    Largely illegible, but begins, "My father gives me the agreeable task of answering your letter... ."
  - Letter - J. R. Washington, to Commodore James Barron, 25 December 1824., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 6:67)
    Re: acts before Congress, including "Col. Johnson's for the abolition of imprisonment for debt and of Mr. Johnson from Louisiana to appropriate all the public land to internal improvement and education in the United States"; and that "either General Jackson or Mr. Adams must be elected (to the Presidency) by Congress."
  - Letter - O. Winchester, Baltimore, to General Robert B. Taylor, Norfolk, Virginia, 29 December 1824., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 6:68)
    Re: the drafting of an unspecified memorial.
  Series 7: Box 7
- Box 7, 1825-1827. (Box-folder 7:1-78)
  Correspondence of the years 1825 to 1827, includes correspondence with A. McLane, Wilmington, Delaware who described his experiences when he accompanied Gen'l Lafayette on a part of his visit to the U.S.; with Charles D. Brodie, Portsmouth, who was enthusiastic about the ventilating system for ships invented by Barron; with Benjamin King, Washington, D.C. about the ventilating system and the pump invented by Barron; with Samuel L. Southard, Secretary of the Navy, and Chas. W. Goldsborough, Secretary of the Naval Command, including a copybook of letters written to them by Barron; and with his daughters, Mrs. Jane Barron Hope and Mrs. Virginia Barron Pendergast. In 1825, Barron returned to Norfolk to command the Naval Post at Gosport, and presided at a Naval Court Martial in Washington. There is a letter from "R.S.," Washington, D.C., reporting a speech made in Congress by John Randolph on The Chesapeake-Leopard Affair and on the Barron-Decatur duel, and one from Andrew Jackson, the Hermitage, asking Barron to serve as proxy godfather for him, 30 June 1827.
  - Letter - D. Winchester, Baltimore Ins. Co., to Gen'l Robert B. Taylor, Norfolk, Virginia, 11 January 1825., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 7:1)
    Re: a memorial to Congress concerned with claims under the Florida Treaty.
  - Letter - Beverly Kennon, U.S. Ship Peacock, Balboa Bay, to Commodore [James] Barron, U.S. Naval Station, Philadelphia, 21 January 1825., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 7:2)
    Congratulations on his appointment; re: his cruise and the independence of Peru.
  - Letter - J. Marron, Norfolk, to Come. James Barron, Philadelphia, 31 January 1825., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 7:3)
    Re: A Negro Man Ned, about who Gen'l Andrew Jackson was concerned.
  - Letters - R. Gatewood, Norfolk, to Como. James Barron, Philadelphia and Washington, January-December 1825., 18 letters. ALsS. (Box-folder 7:4)
    Much news of Naval events in Norfolk, including criticism of the Admiral, the trial of Stewart, letter of Gen'l Jackson to Mr. Clay, and the movement of warships in and out of Norfolk.
  - Letter - W.G. Nicholas, Richmond, to Maj. Gen'l Taylor, Norfolk, 3 February 1825., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 7:5)
    Re: the raising of an army.
  - Letter - W. Bainbridge, Washington, to Commr. James Barron, Philadelphia, 9 February 1825., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 7:6)
    Re: the nephew of Barron, Midshipman [Samuel] Barron.
  - Letter - John Hollins, Maryland Ins. Co., Baltimore, to Robert Taylor, Norfolk, Virginia, 14 February 1825., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 7:7)
    Re: a representation he made to Congress.
  - Notice - J.W. Houston, Philadelphia, to Commodore [James] Barron, 24 February 1825., 1 pages. PADS. (Box-folder 7:8)
    Notice of election to the Musical Fund Society of Philadelphia.
  - James Barron, Philadelphia and Washington, to his daughter, Jane A. Hope, Hampton and Norfolk, February-September 1825., 14 letters. ALsS. (Box-folder 7:9)
    Family letters covering the period in Philadelphia where he commanded the Navy Yard, and his time in Washington as Chairman of a Naval Court Martial.
  - Letters - A. McLane, Wilmington, Delaware, to Commodore James Barron, Washington and Gosport, February-December 1825., 7 letters. ALsS. (Box-folder 7:10)
    A. McLane, a Revolutionary war veteran, writes of his experiences accompanying Gen'l Lafayette on his visits to America.
  - Plea - The mechanics employed in the Navy Yard, Gosport, to Commodore James Barron, Commander of the U.S. Navy Yard, Gosport, 4 March 1825., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 7:11)
    A plea for more regular payment of wages.
  - E.R. McCall, New Brunswick, New Jersey, to Com. James Barron, Philadelphia, 8 March 1825., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 7:12)
    Report of his journey to report for duty.
  - Letter - Charles D. Brodie, Portsmouth, to Commodore James Barron, Philadelphia, 8 March 1825., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 7:13)
    Re: the outfitting of ships; and of Barron's ventilation system, "it may be hailed as the salvation of our Navy."
  - Letter - John Gillespie, Copenhagen, to Commodore James Barron, Philadelphia, 10 March 1825., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 7:14)
  - Letter - J. Gaillard, Charleston, to Commodore James Barron, Philadelphia, 15 April 1825., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 7:15)
    Introducing John Geddes.
  - Letter - J[ames] B[arron], Philadelphia, to Samuel L. Southard, Secretary of the Navy, Washington, D.C., 25 April 1825., 1 page. ADrS. (Box-folder 7:16)
    Recommending Henry Crabb.
  - Letter - Robert Kennedy, Philadelphia, to Com. James Barron, Philadelphia, 25 April 1825., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 7:17)
    Supporting the claims of William Crabb, Assistant Navy Store Keeper.
  - Request - Henry Geddes, to Com. [James] Barron, Philadelphia, 30 April 1825., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 7:18)
    Requesting assistance for the appointment of his son, George, to the Service.
  - Notice - Samuel L. Southard, Navy Department, to Capt. James Barron, Philadelphia, 2 May 1825., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 7:19)
    Notice of transfer of Barron to the command of the Gosport Navy Yard in Virginia.
  - Request - James Renshaw to Commodore James Barron, Philadelphia, 9 May 1825., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 7:20)
    Request for leave.
  - Request - W.W. Buchanan, West Point, New York, to James Barron, Philadelphia, 11 May 1825., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 7:21)
    Request to be placed under the command of Barron.
  - Invitation - Robert Patterson and James M. Broom to Commodore [James] Barron, Philadelphia, 14 May 1825., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 7:22)
    Invitation to a testimonial dinner to be given for Barron on the occasion of his removal from Philadelphia. Enclosure: a toast to Philadelphia.
  - Letter - J.P. Tuttle, Norfolk, to Commodore James Barron, Washington, 19 May 1825., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 7:23)
    Re: family affairs.
  - Letter - J.M. Broom, Philadelphia, to Commodore Ja[me]s Barron, Norfolk, 20 May 1825., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 7:24)
    Regret at Barron's departure from Philadelphia.
  - Request -A. Fibigan, Copenhagen, to James Barron, Philadelphia, 30 May 1825., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 7:25)
    Request advice regarding the milling of flour.
  - Letters - J.D. Elliott, Carlisle and Philadelphia, to Como. James Barron, Philadelphia and Norfolk, May-November 1825., 3 letters. ALsS. (Box-folder 7:26)
    He writes of his difficult situation in the Navy.
  - Invitation - G. Newton and M. King, Cateras, to Commodore James Barron, 30 June 1825., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 7:27)
    Invitation to a dinner.
  - Letters - Benjamin King, Washington, to Comre. James Barron, Gosport, Virginia, June-November 1825., 3 letters. ALsS. (Box-folder 7:28)
    Re: the pump invented by Barron.
  - Letter - Jno. Hollins, Baltimore, to Robert Taylor, Norfolk, 6 July 1825., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 7:29)
    Re: the Florida Treaty.
  - Request - W.W. Buchanan, West Point, to James Barron, Washington, 7 July 1825., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 7:30)
    Request for an assignment.
  - Letter - W[illia]m Allison McRea, Alexandria, to Captain James Barron, U.S. Navy, Washington, D.C., 10 July 1825., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 7:31)
    Offers self as Secretary to Barron who it is rumored is to command the Frigate Brandywine conveying Gen. Lafayette to France.
  - Request - M.S. Moore, Portsmouth, to Commodore James Barron, Washington, 16 July 1825., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 7:32)
    Request for help in getting his back wages from the Navy.
  - Letter - Louis M. Goldsborough, Lt., U.S. Navy, Washington, to Commdre. James Barron, President of the Naval Court Martial, 21 July 1825., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 7:33)
    Reporting as a witness at the court martial of Charles Stewart.
  - Letters - George T. Kennon, Norfolk, to Commodore James Barron, Gosport Navy Yard, July-October 1825., 3 letters. ALsS. (Box-folder 7:34)
    Re: his brother, Dr. Richard Kennon, who is relieved of sea duty and placed under the command of Barron.
  - Letter - John Browere, Washington, to Capt. [James] Barron, Washington, 6 September 1825., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 7:35)
    Submitting his bust of Gen'l Lafayette to the Public Inspector at Washington.
  - Letter - J[ane Barron] Hope, Gosport, to Comdr. James Barron, U.S. Navy, Washington, 17 September 1825., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 7:36)
    Re: the romance of Lt. Pendergrast and Virginia Barron.
  - Letter - James Barron, Philadelphia, to Mrs. Jane A. Hope, Norfolk, 24 September 1825., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 7:37)
    Re: the suitor for the hand of Virginia Barron.
  - Account - Matthew Maury, New York, to Commodore [James] Barron, Norfolk, Virginia, 2 October 1825., 2 items. ALS, Encl. (Box-folder 7:38)
    Enclosing account for services in taking out a patent for Barron on angle-lever-windlass.
  - Letter, 7 October 1825., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 7:39)
    Re: some affairs before Congress - - largely illegible.
  - Letter - Captain Kenyon, Philadelphia, to Commodore James Barron, Norfolk, 13 October 1825., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 7:40)